<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Sylvan&#39;s Abracadabra</title>
    <link>https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Sylvan&#39;s Abracadabra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2023, Sylvan.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZooKeeper Notes</title>
      <link>https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/zookeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 22:15:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/zookeeper/</guid>
      <description>ZooKeeper Notes What is ZK Data Model Architecture Zab Reference Tens of thousands of the applications are running on distributed systems today, where ZooKeeper plays an important role in order to make the whole system work consistently. Here are my notes on it.&#xA;What is ZK ZK provides the uses a consistent view of a distributed system, and building blocks for synchronization across a cluster of nodes. For example, it has the ability to save the meta information, such as membership configurations, of a cluster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; Coroutine Notes</title>
      <link>https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/cxx-coro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 23:01:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/cxx-coro/</guid>
      <description>C++ Coroutine Notes Stackful vs Stackless The Coroutine Handles/Objects Coroutine Handle Awaiter promise_type The Coroutine Operators co_await co_yield co_return Reference The funtinality of coroutine in C++ is more of a semi-finished product. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide the users a handy way to invoke a coroutine. For instance, in Golang, we can set off a goroutine readily by letting go of any functions. On the contrary, C++&amp;rsquo;s post-20 standards come with some &amp;lsquo;gadgets&amp;rsquo; which are the building blocks for the programmers to build a fully functioning architecture of coroutine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inverted Index Notes</title>
      <link>https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/inv-idx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 23:34:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://meteoryee.github.io/tech/inv-idx/</guid>
      <description>Inverted Index Notes The Definition The File Organization Optimizations Cache Compression Smart Traversing Reference I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on inverted index these days. Hence, it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to do some summaries on it. I am going to split the notes into three parts: what is an inverted index, the possible file organization of it, and some of the optimizations to enhance its working efficiency.&#xA;The Definition As the name shows, it&amp;rsquo;s inverted, but what is the inversion meant to be?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
